

**Daniel Banciu** 

M.Sc. Computer Scence

- Steinenbronner Str. 15, 71101 Schönaich, Germany
- **&** +49 1573 31 91 308
- @ daniel02\_banciu@yahoo.de

#### Skills

## Backend Development

Java, Python, Springboot/ VertX, REST

Machine Learning

Data Science

Frontend

Development

ReactJS, HTML/CSS

Classification, Regression, Vision-Transformers, deeplearning-weatherprediction models, CNN explainable AI, Correlation, Patterns

#### Awards

## Deutschlandstipendium (scholarship) 2019-2020

#### Languages

**German** Native

**English** Fluent Romanian

Native

Italian A2

Newly graduated Masters student at the University of Tübingen. I am running my own business as an external data protection consultant. Been working both full time and part time as a software developer since 2020. I am very communicative and ambitious.

#### Profiles

dbanciu GitHub in <u>daniel-banciu</u> LinkedIn

#### Education

#### University of Tübingen

Computer Science

https://uni-tuebingen.de/en/

Tübingen, Germany

#### **Heilbronn University of Applied Sciences**

Software Engineering

https://www.hs-heilbronn.de/en

Heilbronn, Germany

Immanuel-Kant-Gymnasium

ander-Kant-Oyninasium

Leinfelden-Echterdingen, Germany

#### Experience

#### Vector Informatik GmbH

Software Developer

https://www.vector.com/de/de/

Bachelor Thesis, Full-Time between Bachelor's and Master's, working student.

## eXXcellent solutions consulting & software GmbH

Software Developer

https://www.exxcellent.de/

Internship and working student.

#### **Own small Side Business**

External data protection consultant

External data protection consultant and IT consultant specialised for dentists .

#### **Theses**

Exploring Latent 2023-2024
Representations for Tübingen, Germany

Identifying Forecasting

Opportunities in Deep

**Learning Weather Models** 

Master Thesis

Investigated the predictive capabilities of FourCastNet, a deep learning weather prediction model, focusing on its utilisation of the Madden-Julian Oscillation (MJO) for enhancing weather forecast accuracy. Analysed predictive performance metrics such as root-mean-square-error and anomaly correlation coefficient.

Data Science, Machine Learning, Python

Predictive Analysis of

**Electric Vehicles during** Heilbronn, Germany

October 2021 - April 2024

September 2017 - August 2021

November 2020 - March 2023

February 2020 - October 2020

Stuttgart, Germany

Stuttgart, Germany

April 2018 - Present

2021

Master of Science

Bachelor of Science

2009-2017

High School

Charging to Optimize
Load Management

Algorithms

Bachelor Thesis at

Vector GmbH

Developed a critical feature for the vCharM system by Vector Informatik GmbH to enhance load management in electric vehicle charging networks. This feature involved gathering and analyzing vehicle charging data to refine load management algorithms, thereby optimizing power grid operations in residential and company settings.

Java, FullStack

Volunteering
<b>Digitale Sprechstunde</b> <b>2020</b> Stuttgart, Germany
Helping old people with all IT-related things such as setting up their smartphone and explaining how to write e-mails etc
Jugendgemeinderat (local politics youth council) founding member 2016 Leinfelden-Echterdingen, Germany
Interests
Karate Jiu Jitsu
Karate Jiu Jitsu E-Sports Gym

## Projects

# Fair Machine Learning 2023 Seminar

Course at Tübingen

Evaluation the effectiveness of attribution methods for tabular data. Comparing the performance of SHAP and LIME attribution methods. Using a transformer-based language model, known as GReaT.

Machine Learning, explainable Al

2023

**Self Driving Cars** 

Machine Learning

Self Driving Cars

course at Tübingen

Challenges involved

imitation learning and

reinforcement learning using

the car gym environment.

Machine Learning, PyTorch,

Imitation Learning, Reinforcement Learning

Challenges

### Pose Estimation Machine Learning

Course Project of "ML and Vision" at Tübingen

As part of the course "Praktikum Bildverarbeitung, Maschinelles Lernen und Computer Vision" we show how we developed a pytorch implementation of the paper 'Toward fast and accurate human pose estimation via soft-gated skip connections'.

Machine Learning, CNN, PyTorch

#### BUGA 2019 App Bachelor's "big project" at Heilbronn

Development of an application for the Bundesgartenschau 2019 in Heilbronn as part of the big project in the 5th semester of the bachelor's degree.

Fullstack, Java, React, Scrum

## NLP Analysis

2022

2019

Course Project of "Data Literacy" at Tübingen

2022

Analysis of an unknown data set in a project in teams of two. We analysed every speech in the Bundestag and tried to answer questions like "How has the language developed?"

Data Science, NLP